Guide to the Felix Bloch Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- ORGANIZATIONS, SERIES IV
  - CAMBRIDGE PHILOSOPHICAL SOCIETY.
    - Correspondence, (1967). (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - CITIZENS FOR HUMPHREY.
    - Correspondence, (1968). (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - COMMITTEE FOR UN INTEGRITY.
    - Correspondence, (1980). (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - ENCOUNTER FOR THE UNIVERSALITY OF UNESCO.
    - UNESCO. Correspondence, (1975-76). (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - UNESCO. Miscellaneous publications. (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - AMERICAN PHYSICAL SOCIETY.
    - APS. Outgoing correspondence, (1955-February 1965). (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - APS. Outgoing, (March 1965). (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - APS. Outgoing, (April-May 1965). (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - APS. Outgoing, (June-September 1965). (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - APS. Outgoing, (October-November 1965). (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - APS. Outgoing, (December 1965-October 1971). (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - APS. Incoming correspondence (Bashkin). (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - APS. Incoming (B-C). (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - APS. Incoming (Darrow, K.). (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - APS. Incoming (D-N). (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - APS. Incoming (Quimby, S.). (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - APS. Incoming (R-W). (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - APS. Incoming (Wheeler). (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/64 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/64 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 10/64 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 10/64 Council. Appendix to minutes. (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/65 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/65 General. (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/65 General. Program. (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - APS. Meeting. Oklahoma 2/65 General. (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - APS. Meeting. Kansas City 3/65 General. (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/65 Council. Correspondence, (9/64-3/65). (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/65 Council. Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/65 Council. Correspondence, (5/65). (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/65 Council. Agenda. (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/65 General. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 6/65 General. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - APS. Meeting. Hawaii 9/65 General. Correspondence, (9/63-1/65). (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - APS. Meeting. Hawaii 9/65 General. Correspondence, (2-3/65). (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - APS. Meeting. Hawaii 9/65 General. Correspondence, (3/65). (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - APS. Meeting. Hawaii 9/65 General. Correspondence, (4-5/65). (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - APS. Meeting. Hawaii 9/65 General. Correspondence, (5/65). (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - APS. Meeting. Hawaii 9/65 General. Correspondence, (6-7/65). (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - APS. Meeting. Hawaii 9/65 General. Correspondence, (8/65-2/66). (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 10/65 Council. (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 10/65 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 10/65 General. (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - APS. Meeting. Los Angeles 12/65 General. (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/66 Council. Correspondence, (5/65-1/66). (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/66 Council. Correspondence, (1-3/66). (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/66 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/66 General. (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/66 Council. (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/66 Council. Minutes. (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - APS. Meeting. Nashville 12/66 Council. Correspondence, (9-11/66). (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - APS. Meeting. Nashville 12/66 Council. Correspondence (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - APS. Meeting. Nashville 12/66 Council. Preliminary agenda. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - APS. Meeting. Nashville 12/66 Council. Agenda. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - APS. Meeting. Nashville 12/66 Council. Minutes. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - APS. Meeting. Nashville 12/66 Council. Notes on the amendments to the Ohio section. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/67 Council. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/67 Council. Preliminary agenda. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/67 Council. Final agenda. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/67 General. Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/67 General. Draft of minutes. (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 1/67 General. Appendix to minutes. (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/67 Council. Agenda. (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/67 Council. Correspondence, (12/66-3/67). (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/67 Council. Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/67 Council. Minutes. (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/67 Council. Expense receipts. (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/68 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/68 Council. Appendix to minutes. (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - APS. Meeting. Miami 11/68 Council. Report and agenda. (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - APS. Meeting. San Diego 12/68 General. Bulletin. (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 2/69 Council. Agenda. (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 2/69 Council. Minutes. (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/69 Council. Minutes. (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - APS. Meeting. Boulder 11/69 Council; Agenda and minutes. New York 1/71 Council; Agenda. Atlantic City 3/72; Memo. (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 1/70 General. Miscellaneous. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 1/70 General. Minutes. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - APS. Meeting. Chicago 1/70 General. Minutes. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/70 Council. Agenda and minutes. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - APS. Meeting. Washington 4/70 Council. Minutes. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 8/70 Council. Minutes and miscellaneous. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 11/70 Council. Agenda, report, and minutes. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - APS. Meeting. New York 11/70 Council. Treasurer's report. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - APS. Committees. Bonner Prize. (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - APS. Committees. Buckley Prize. (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - APS. Committees. Committee on the Character of APS Meetings (CAPSICUM). Correspondence, (2-7/65). (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - APS. Committees. CAPSICUM. Correspondence, (8-9/65). (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - APS. Committees. CAPSICUM. Correspondence, (10/65-5/66). (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - APS. Committees. CAPSICUM. Correspondence, (6-9/66). (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - APS. Committees. CAPSICUM. Correspondence, (10/66-5/67). (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - APS. Committees. Committee on the Revision of the APS Constitution (CRAC). Correspondence, (4-11/65). (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (12/65). (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (1/66). (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (2-3/66). (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (3/66). (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (4/66). (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (4-5/66). (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (7-8/66). (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - APS. Committees. CRAC. Correspondence, (8/66-5/68). (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (9/63-4/64). (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (4/6-64). (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (6-9/64). (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (10/64-1/65). (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (1/66-7/68). (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (7-10/68). (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (11/68-1/69). (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (6-12/69). (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (1-4/70). (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (6/70). (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (7/70). (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Correspondence, (8/70-1/71). (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Auditor's Report, (1963). (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Auditor's Report, (1964). (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Auditor's Report, (1967). (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - APS. Committees. Council. Auditor's Report, (1968). (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - APS. Committees. Davisson-Germer Prize. (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - APS. Committees. Heineman Prize. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - APS. Committees. High Energy Physics Association (HEPA). Correspondence, (4-7/65). (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - APS. Committees. HEPA. Correspondence, (8/65-2/66). (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - APS. Committees. HEPA. Proposal. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - APS. Committees. Nuclear Physics. Correspondence, (3-11/65). (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - APS. Committees. Publications Committee. (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - APS. Committees. Revision of Physical Review. Correspondence. (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - APS. Committees. Advisory Committee on Fellowship Nominations. (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - APS. Committees. History of Quantum Physics. (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - APS. Committees. Nominating Committee. Correspondence, (1-3/66). (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - APS. Committees. Nominating Committee. Correspondence, (4-5/66). (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - APS. Committees. Nominating Committee. Nominations, (1967). (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - APS. Committees. Organization of the APS. (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - APS. Committees. Representative of the APS on USANCIUPAP. (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - APS. Survey of Salaries of APS Officers. (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - COMMITTEE OF CONCERNED SCIENTISTS (CCS).
    - CCS. Correspondence, (5-8/1979). (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (12/79-4/80). (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (5-8/1980). (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (11/80-2/81). (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (3-6/1981). (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (7-11/1981). (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (12/81-5-82). (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (6-12/1982). (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (1-2/1983). (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - CCS. Correspondence, (3-7/1983). (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY OF MAGNETIC RESONANCE.
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (3/69-12/71). (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (3-12/1972). (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence List of members., (1/1973). (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (2-6/1973). (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (7-12/1973). (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (1-4/1974). (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (9/74-12/75). (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (12/76-12/78). (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (1/79-2/82). (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (3-8/1982). (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (9/1982). (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (10 1-7/1982). (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (10 8-13/1982). (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (10 15-20/1982). (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (10 21-30/1982). (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (11/1982). (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (12/1982). (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (1-5/1983). (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - ISMAR. Correspondence, (6-7/1983). (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - ISMAR. Program announcements. IVth and Vth meetings. (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - ISMAR. Program announcements. VIth meeting. (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - ISMAR. Program announcements. VIII meeting. (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - ISMAR. Miscellaneous. (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - ISMAR. Miscellaneous receipts. (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - ISMAR. Constitution. (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - JEWISH HALL OF FAME. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - KURATORIUM FUR DIE TAGUNGEN DER NOBELPREISTRAGER
    - KTN. Outgoing correspondence, (1955-82). (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - KTN. Incoming correspondence (Bernadotte). (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - KTN. Incoming correspondence (F-S). (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - KTN. Programs. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES.
    - NAS. Outgoing correspondence, (1948-71). (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - NAS. Incoming correspondence (A-W). (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - NAS. Programs, (1966, 1973). (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION.
    - Correspondence, (1952-69). (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - NEW YORK ACADEMY OF SCIENCES.
    - Correspondence, (1968). (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - NOBELSTIFTELSEN.
    - Correspondence, (1968-1975). (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - ORDEN POUR LE MERITE FUR WISSENSCHAFTEN UND KUNSTE (OMWK).
    - OMWK. Correspondence, (11/71-8/79). (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - OMWK. Correspondence, (9/79-3/80). (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - OMWK. Correspondence, (6/80-5/81). (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - OMWK. Correspondence, (6/81-3/82). (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - OMWK. Correspondence, (4-8/1982). (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - OMWK. Correspondence, (9/82-6/83). (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - ROYAL NETHERLANDS ACADEMY OF ARTS AND SCIENCES.
    - Correspondence, (1974-78). (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - ROYAL SOCIETY OF EDINBURGH.
    - Correspondence and Yearbook, (1975) (1966). (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - SOCIETY OF THE SIGMA XI.
    - Program and announcements, (1959-76). (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - SOCIETE FRANCAISE DE PHYSIQUE.
    - Correspondence, (1967-74). (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - SOCIETE SUISSE DE PHYSIQUE.
    - Programs, (1963). (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - SWEDISH ROYAL ACADEMY: NOBEL COMMITTEE.
    - Correspondence, (1945-64). (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - TATA INSTITUTE OF FUNDAMENTAL RESEARCH.
    - Correspondence, (1970-79). (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - UNION OF CONCERNED SCIENTISTS.
    - Correspondence, (1975). (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - UNIVERSITIES' NATIONAL ANTI-WAR FUND.
    - Correspondence, (1970). (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - SCIENTISTS AND ENGINEERS FOR SECURE ENERGY (SESE).
    - SESE. Outgoing, (1975-80). (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - SESE. Incoming (A-C). (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - SESE. Incoming (D-M). (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - SESE. Incoming (O-T). (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - SESE. Incoming (Todorovich, 1976-80). (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - SESE. Incoming (Todorovich, 1981). (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - SESE. Incoming (Todorovich, 1982). (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - SESE. Weekly Reports, (1975). (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - SESE. Status Updates. (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - SESE. SENSE newsletters. (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - SESE. Miscellaneous publications and articles. (Box 44, Folder 11)
- PUBLICATIONS, SERIES V
  This series is composed of two sections: one contains reprints of all of the articles published by Felix Bloch; the other, a selection from Bloch's collection of reprints by various authors.
  - REPRINTS
    In this section, folders are arranged chronologically, with dates ranging from 1928 to 1982; each folder contains a single article. Most of the articles are reports of Bloch's research and were originally published in scientific journals. Some, however, are nonscientific in nature (i.e. tributes to colleagues, review articles for the educated public).
    - Zur Strahlungsdampfung in der Quantenmechanik, Phys. Zeits. 29 58-66., (1928) (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Uber die Quantenmechanik der Elektronen in Kristallgittern, Zeits. f. Physik 52.7-8 555-600., (1928) (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Zur Quantenmechanik der elektrischen Leitfahigkeit der Metalle, Helv. Phys. 1 466-467., (1929) (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Zur Suszeptibilitat und Widerstandsanderung der Metalle im Magnetfeld, Zeits. f. Physik 53.3-4 216-227., (1929) (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Bemerkung zur Elektronentheorie des Ferromagnetismus und der elektrischen Leitfahigkeit, Zeits. f. Physik 57.7-8 545-555., (1929) (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Zum Elektrischen Widerstandsgesetz bei tiefen Temperaturen, Zeits. f. Physik 59.3-4 208-214., (1930) (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Uber die Wechselwirkung der Metallelektronen, Leipziger Vortrage 1930 67-74. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Zur Theorie des Ferromagnetismus, Zeits. f. Physik 61.3-4 206-219., (1930) (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Ferromagnetisme en Quantum Mechanica, Physica 10.5 153-164., (1930) (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Zur [UNK] der Magnetisierung ferromagnetischer Einkristalle, (with G. Gentile) Zeits.f. Physik 70.5-6 395-408., (1931) (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Wellenmechanische Diskussion der Leitungsund Photoeffekte, Phys.Zeits. 32 881-886., (1931) (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Zur Theorie des Austauschproblems und der Remanenzerscheinung der Ferromagnetika, Zeits. f. Physik 74.5-6 295-335., (1932) (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Zur Bremsung rasch bewegter Teilchen beim Durchgang durch Materie, Ann. d. Physik 16.3 285-320., (1933) (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Bremsvermogen von Atomen mit mehreren Elektronen, Zeits. f. Physik 81.5-6 363-376., (1933) (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Remarque sur un Theoreme de Conversation dans la Theorie des Metaux, Le Journal de Physique et le Radium 4.8 486-491., (1933) (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Die Elektronentheorie der Metalle, Handbuch der Radiologie 6.1-2 226-278., (1933) (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Die physikalische Bedeutung mehrerer Zeiten in der Quantenelektrodynamik, Phys. Zeits. d'Sowjetunion 5.2 301-315., (1934) (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Inkoharente Rontgenstreuung und Dichteschwankungen eines entarteten Fermigases, Helv. Phys. Acta 7.4 385-405., (1934) (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Theory of the Compton-Line, Phys. Rev. 46 674-687., (1934) (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Molekulartheorie des Magnetismus, Handbuch der Radiologie 6.2, 2nd edition, 375-484. (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Radiative Auger Effect, (with P. A. Ross) Phys. Rev. 47 884-885 (L)., (1935) (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Double Electron Transitions in X-ray Spectra, Phys. Rev. 48 187-192., (1935) (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - On the Mechanism of Unimolecular Electron Capture, (with N. E. Bradbury) Phys. Rev. 48 689-695., (1935) (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Recoil by Beta-decay, (with C. Moller) Nature 911., (December 1935) (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Production of Neutrons by Annihilations of Protons and Electrons According to Fermi's Theory, (with C. Moller) Nature 986., (December 1935) (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - On the Magnetic Scattering of Neutrons, Phys. Rev. 50 259 (L). On the Probability of Gamma-ray emission, (with G. Gamow) Phys. Rev. 50 260 (L)., (1936), (1936) (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - On the Continuous Gamma-Radiation Accompanying the Beta-decay, Phys. Rev. 50 272-278., (1936) (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - On the Magnetic Scattering of Neutrons II, Phys. Rev. 51 994 (L)., (1937) (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Note on the Radiation Field of the Electron, (with A. Nordsieck) Phys. Rev. 52 54-59., (1937) (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - The Scattering and Absorption Cross Section of Neutrons in Cobalt, (with Bradbury, Tatel, and Ross) Phys. Rev. 52 256 (A); 52 1023-1026., (1937), (1937) (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - A Deuteron Source for Nuclear Research, (with N. E. Bradbury) American Physical Society abstracts 256 (A)., (1937) (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - On the Temperature Dependence of the Scattering of Slow Neutrons in Ferromagnetics, Phys. Rev. 55 1118 (A)., (1939) (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Quantitative Determination of the Neutron Moment in Absolute Nuclear Magnetons, (with L. W. Alvarez) Phys. Rev. 57 111-122; 57 352 (A)., (1940), (1940) (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Le Moment Magnetique du Neutron, Annales de l'Institut Henri Poincare VIII 63-78., (1940) (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - The Magnetic Moment of the Neutron, (with L. W. Alvarez). Phys. Rev. 57 352 (A)., (1940) (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Magnetic Resonance for Nonrotating Fields, (with A. Siegert) Phys. Rev. 57 522-527., (1940) (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Theory of the Resonance Scattering of Protons and Neutrons on Helium, Phys. Rev. 58 829-836., (1940) (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - Further Results on Magnetic Scattering of Neutrons, (with M. Hammermesh) Phys. Rev. 61 203 (A)., (1942) (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - Reduction of the Problem of Arbitrary Spin to that of Spin 1/2, Phys. Rev. 62 305 (A)., (1942) (Box 45, Folder 39)
    - Neutron Polarization and Ferromagnetic Saturation, (with M. Hamermesh and H. Staub) Phys. Rev. 62 303 (A); 64 47-56., (1942), (1943) (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - Atoms in Variable Magnetic Fields, (with I. I. Rabi) Rev. Mod. Phys. 17 237-244., (1945) (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - Nuclear Induction, (with W. W. Hansen and M. Packard) Phys. Rev. 69 127 (L); 69 680 (A)., (1946), (1946) (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - Nuclear Induction, Phys. Rev. 70 460-474., (1946) (Box 45, Folder 43)
    - The Nuclear Induction Experiment, (with W. W. Hansen and M. Packard) Phys. Rev. 70 474-485., (1946) (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - Neutron Polarization and Ferromagnetic Saturation, (with R. I. Condit and H. H. Staub) Phys. Rev. 70 972-973., (1946) (Box 45, Folder 45)
    - Radar Reflections from Long Conductors, Journal of Appl. Phys. 17 1015-1020., (1946) (Box 45, Folder 46)
    - Theory of Radar Reflection from Wires or Thin Metallic Strips, (with J. H. Van Vleck and M. Hamermesh) J. Appl. Phys. 18.3 274-294., (1947) (Box 45, Folder 47)
    - Spin and Magnetic Moment of Tritium, (with Graves, Packard and Spence) Phys. Rev. 71 373 (L)., (1947) (Box 45, Folder 48)
    - Relative Moments of H1 and H3, (with Graves, Packard, and Spence) Phys. Rev. 71 551 (L)., (1947) (Box 45, Folder 49)
    - Relative Nuclear Moments of H1 and H2, (with E. C. Levinthal and M. E. Packard) Phys. Rev. 72 1125-1126 (L)., (1947) (Box 45, Folder 50)
    - A Quantitative Determination of the Magnetic Moment of the Neutron in Units of the Proton Moment, (with D. Nicodemus and H. H. Staub) Phys. Rev. 74 1025-1045., (1948) (Box 45, Folder 51)
    - Nuclear Induction Proton Signals Below Noise Level from Gases at One Atmosphere, (with D. H. Garber) Phys. Rev. 76 585 (A)., (1949) (Box 45, Folder 52)
    - The Differential Equations of Nuclear Induction, (with R. K. Wangsness) Phys. Rev. 78 82 (A)., (1950) (Box 45, Folder 53)
    - Polarization Effects of Scattered Neutrons, (with W. E. Meyerhof and D. B. Nicodemus) Phys. Rev. 80 132 (A)., (1950) (Box 45, Folder 54)
    - A Direct Determination of the Magnetic Moment of the Proton in Nuclear Magnetons, (with C. D. Jeffries) Phys. Rev. 80 305-306 (L)., (1950) (Box 45, Folder 55)
    - Nuclear Induction, Phys. Today 3.8 22., (1950) (Box 45, Folder 56)
    - Nuclear Induction, Physica 17.3-4 272-281., (1951) (Box 45, Folder 57)
    - Electronic Theory of the Cylindrical Magneton (with L. Brillouin), Advances in Electronics 3 145-181., (1951) (Box 45, Folder 58)
    - Magnetic Moments of Even-Odd Nuclei, Phys. Rev. 83 839 (L)., (1951) (Box 45, Folder 59)
    - Nuclear Relaxation in Gases by Surface Catalysis, Phys. Rev. 83 1062-1063 (L)., (1951) (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - William Webster Hansen, National Academy of Sciences' Biographical Memoirs XXVII 118-137., (1952) (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - The Dynamical Theory of Nuclear Induction, (with R. K. Wangsness) Phys. Rev. 89 728-739., (1953) (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Experiments on the g-factor of the Electron, Physica XIX 821-831., (1953) (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Das Prinzip der Kerninduktion, Phys. Blatter 9 433., (1953) (Box 46, Folder 5)